<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-31T09:00:36+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shubham Tomar</title><subtitle>A collection of thoughts</subtitle><author><name>Shubham Tomar</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Disease of Obsession</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/obsession/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Disease of Obsession" /><published>2024-12-26T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-12-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/obsession</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/obsession/"><![CDATA[<p>We often discuss work-life balance, but rarely work-life obsession. Yet every great achievement stems from someone’s inability to let go, to stop thinking, to “switch off.”</p>

<p>Obsession gets a bad rap. We celebrate the outcomes—the breakthrough products, the elegant solutions, the market-defining companies—while condemning the mindset that birthed them. This cognitive dissonance serves no one.</p>

<p>Here’s what obsession really means: you keep working on the problem in the shower. You wake up with solutions. Your mind constantly reorganizes information, finding new patterns, better approaches. You can’t help it. The problem has infected you.</p>

<p>This isn’t about hours worked. It’s about mental real estate occupied. When you’re genuinely obsessed with your craft, ego dissolves. Pride emerges not from being better than others, but from the work itself meeting your own standards.</p>

<p>The question isn’t whether to be obsessed, but what to be obsessed with. Choose wisely. The disease is beautiful, but it’s still a disease. Make sure it’s one worth having.</p>]]></content><author><name>Shubham Tomar</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We often discuss work-life balance, but rarely work-life obsession. Yet every great achievement stems from someone’s inability to let go, to stop thinking, to “switch off.”]]></summary></entry></feed>